TIMOTHY M. WALSH

(917) 304-2597 tim@walsh.consulting

11 Mason Ave Lincoln Park, NJ 07035

Senior financial executive with unique experience managing all aspects of a closely held business as well as the related family office. Served in various capacities including Vice-President and CFO of the operating business, trustee of the family trusts, board member and overall trusted family advisor.

HIGHLIGHTS AND KEY STRENGTHS

- Experienced CFO of a mid-size, family owned media company
- CEO of embedded family office for high profile family for over 20 years
- Trustee of family trusts
- Led team of investment bankers, lawyers, and accountants in sale of several media properties
- Issued and refinanced debt in public markets on several occasions for operating business, including presentation to S&P and Moody's
- Experienced in negotiating joint ventures with competing media companies
- Involved in all aspects of extensive family estate plan
- Managed tax department for family and operating entities consisting of a series of flow through entities
- Experienced managing all business-related departments of the operating company
- Experienced in all areas of family office management including banking, investments, cash management, bill payment, reporting, insurance, aviation and construction management
- Organized, analytical, detail oriented, problem solver
- Highly motivated, tireless worker, and committed team leader who leads by example

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Walsh Consulting, New York, NY Founder & CEO

2019 Current

- Formed entity to lead the wind-down of the Wenner Media businesses, including filing final income tax returns, liquidating entities, terminating retirement plans and distributing assets
- Continue to manage Wenner family investments, tax return preparation, cash management, insurance coverage, estate planning, reporting and bill payment.

Wenner Media, New York, NY Vice-President, CFO & Board Member 1991 to 2018 *27 years*

- Led team responsible for the sale of *Us Weekly*, *Men's Journal* and *Rolling Stone*, including managing relationships with investment banking, legal, accounting and creditor teams
- Led team responsible for financing and refinancing of term loans in the public markets on several occasions, including presentation to S&P, Moody's and investor group
- Negotiated and finalized the formation of a joint venture for the sale of a minority interest in *Rolling Stone* to a Singapore-based entity
- Managed costs aggressively with the contraction of the print media business including outsourcing of various departments, while working to develop other revenue streams and transitioning to a more digitally focused business
- Responsible for setting policy and managing roughly 100 staff in the Finance, Tax, Legal, Human Resources, IT, Payroll, Licensing, Circulation, IT, Manufacturing and Facilities departments
- Responsible for all financial reporting and analysis, including budgeting, quarterly presentations to debt holders and audited financial statements
- Reviewed strategic investment opportunities for the company and the family
- Responsible for retirement plans including investments, testing, tax return preparation and annual audits
- Experienced in negotiating contracts in all facets of publishing business including employee benefit plans, real estate leases, international and product licensing, paper, printing and distribution contracts

Wenner Media, New York, NY Management of Family Office

2000 to 2018 18 yrs. concurrently

- Led family office in all financial matters
- Trustee of numerous family trusts
- Led team responsible for income tax planning and compliance for a series of S corps., partnerships, LLCs, trusts and individuals
- Participated in all areas of estate planning including review of planning opportunities, running cash flow analysis, reviewing wills and trusts and presentation to the family
- Responsible for ongoing activities of the trusts including cash flow, debt obligations, investments and distributions to family members
- Worked with investment advisers to ensure investments meet family expectations and aligned with the family risk tolerance
- Met with advisors quarterly to review performance, reconcile asset levels to cash flow, review suggested additions or subtractions from portfolios and report to the family
- Responsible for cash management for the family including distributions from operating companies for income tax payments, personal expenditures and investments
- Responsible for payment of and accounting for family expenditures, quarterly reporting and annual budgets, while ensuring that proper safeguards are in place both from a personnel and technology standpoint

- Maintained banking relationships for establishment and maintenance of accounts, lines-of-credit, etc.
- Responsible for managing residential construction projects including interfacing with architects, contractors and attorneys, while controlling timelines and budgets
- Responsible for aircraft including structuring for optimum sales and income tax treatment, hiring personnel, negotiating management and maintenance agreements, and ensuring proper use of the aircraft under Part 91 and Part 135
- Responsible for acquiring insurance and managing risk for homes, artwork collections, jewelry, automobiles and excess liability
- Responsible for household payroll, complying with all employment laws and maintaining appropriate employment insurance coverage
- Instituted procedures for maintaining all sensitive family documents, logins and passwords in a secure, encrypted cloud-based environment

Ernst & Young, LLP, New York, NY Manager, Tax Department

1986 to 1991 5 yrs.

- Provided tax advisory and compliance services for many clients
- Focused primarily on partnership, S Corps and other flow-through entities

EDUCATION

MS	Pace University, Lubin School of Business Taxation	1993
BS	Widener University Accounting	1985
Certified Public Accountant New York		1993
PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS		

American Institute of Certified Public Accountants

REFERENCES

Excellent references available upon request